=Light of Dawn=
=نور الفجر=
(Muke Club)
(نحن نادٍ)
I honestly don't know
بصراحة لا أعرف
when your mother gave birth to you.
عندما أنجبتك والدتك.
When I went to the attic to get the truth,
عندما صعدت إلى العلية لأعرف الحقيقة،
she was already dead.
كانت قد ماتت بالفعل.
My guess is
أظن أن
that she and Feifei's mom
أنها ووالدة فيفي
were pregnant around the same time.
كانتا حاملتين في نفس الوقت تقريباً.
They were tight back then.
كانوا متماسكين آنذاك.
Inseparable. (Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org)
لا ينفصلان. (يمكنكم متابعة الدعم الإداري على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org)
Like they were joined at the hip.
كأنهم ملتصقون ببعضهم البعض.
You get what I mean?
هل فهمت قصدي؟
Just like you,
مثلك تماماً،
I was kept in the dark, too.
لقد تم إبقائي في الظلام أيضاً.
(Early 1990s)
(أوائل التسعينيات)
Golden Ball Angel, Qu Meng,
ملاك الكرة الذهبية، كو مينغ
has recovered from an illness
تعافى من المرض
and returns to the stage.
ثم يعود إلى المسرح.
Let's welcome her with a round of applause!
فلنرحب بها بالتصفيق الحار!
Thank you, Ms. Hong.
شكراً لكِ يا آنسة هونغ.
Without her,
بدونها،
I wouldn't be who I am today.
ما كنت لأكون ما أنا عليه اليوم.
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدًا،
we'll face a brand-new start together.
سنواجه بداية جديدة تمامًا معًا.
Today, I'd like to invite her to sing a song with me
أود اليوم أن أدعوها لغناء أغنية معي
and say goodbye to the past.
وقل وداعاً للماضي.
Please welcome the Queen of the Golden Ball,
يرجى الترحيب بملكة الحفل الذهبي،
Hongyue!
هونغيو!
- Bravo!
- أحسنت!
♪My silent lips♪
شفتاي الصامتتان
♪Stained with tears♪
♪ملطخة بالدموع♪
♪No rouge ♪
♪لا أحمر شفاه♪
♪Can hide these scars♪
♪يمكن إخفاء هذه الندوب♪
♪My heart is broken♪
قلبي محطم
♪How many loves has it lost?♪
♪كم عدد الحب الذي فقدته؟♪
♪Lies meant to make amends♪
♪أكاذيب تهدف إلى إصلاح الأمور♪
♪Excuses meant to atone♪
♪أعذار تهدف إلى التكفير♪
♪I won't take them seriously♪
♪لن آخذهم على محمل الجد♪
♪Love is a journey of the heart♪
♪الحب رحلة القلب♪
♪It means for just the two of us♪
♪هذا يعني لنا نحن الاثنين فقط♪
♪I can't be left wandering alone♪
لا يمكنني أن أبقى أتجول وحيداً
♪Nor should there be three♪
♪ولا ينبغي أن يكون هناك ثلاثة♪
♪You're free to find new love♪
♪ لديك الحرية في العثور على حب جديد ♪
♪Or leave without a word♪
♪أو يرحل دون أن ينبس ببنت شفة♪
♪But don't use atonement as an excuse♪
♪لكن لا تستخدم التكفير كذريعة♪
♪To break my heart again♪
♪لأن يكسر قلبي مرة أخرى♪
♪Tearful eyes♪
♪عيون دامعة♪
♪Reddened by tears♪
♪محمرّ الوجه من الدموع♪
♪How many years will it take♪
♪كم من السنوات سيستغرق ذلك؟♪
♪To forget this love?♪
♪هل ننسى هذا الحب؟♪
♪The fragile heart of mine♪
♪يا قلبي الرقيق♪
♪Still bears your scars♪
♪لا تزال تحمل ندوبك♪
♪Lies meant to make amends♪
♪أكاذيب تهدف إلى إصلاح الأمور♪
♪Excuses meant to atone♪
♪أعذار تهدف إلى التكفير♪
♪How could I ever believe them?♪
كيف لي أن أصدقهم؟
(I've read Yang Wenyuan's novel.)
(لقد قرأت رواية يانغ وينيوان.)
(I'm the one who sang on trains.)
(أنا من كنت أغني في القطارات.)
(He said if one day,)
(قال: إذا حدث ذلك يوماً ما،)
(we got separated,)
(انفصلنا،)
(as long as I went back to the old place and sang,)
(طالما أنني عدت إلى المكان القديم وغنيت،)
(he would come back.)
(سيعود).
♪I once listened patiently as you explained yourself♪
♪استمعتُ إليك بصبرٍ وأنت تشرح نفسك♪
♪And chose to understand♪
♪واختار أن يفهم♪
♪Please don't use atonement as an excuse♪
♪رجاءً لا تستخدموا التكفير كذريعة♪
♪To wound my pride♪
♪لجرح كبريائي♪
♪Love is a journey of the heart♪
♪الحب رحلة القلب♪
♪It means for just the two of us♪
♪هذا يعني لنا نحن الاثنين فقط♪
♪I can't be left wandering alone♪
لا يمكنني أن أبقى أتجول وحيداً
♪Nor should there be three♪
♪ولا ينبغي أن يكون هناك ثلاثة♪
♪You're free to find new love♪
♪ لديك الحرية في العثور على حب جديد ♪
♪Or leave without a word♪
♪أو يرحل دون أن ينبس ببنت شفة♪
♪But don't use atonement as an excuse♪
♪لكن لا تستخدم التكفير كذريعة♪
♪To break my heart again♪
♪لأن يكسر قلبي مرة أخرى♪
I don't know how your mother gave birth to you either.
لا أعرف كيف أنجبتك والدتك أيضاً.
She was remarkable.
كانت رائعة.
If I were you,
لو كنت مكانك،
I'd live well.
سأعيش حياة طيبة.
After your mother passed away,
بعد وفاة والدتك،
Feifei's mom
والدة فيفي
tried to stand up for her.
حاولتُ الدفاع عنها.
She caused trouble a few times.
لقد تسببت في بعض المشاكل عدة مرات.
I was worried about her safety
كنت قلقاً على سلامتها
and afraid she'd stir things up,
وخائفة من أن تُثير المشاكل،
so I had no choice
لذلك لم يكن لدي خيار
but to lock her up.
لكن حبسها.
She left a letter
تركت رسالة
and ran away.
وهرب.
For all these years,
طوال هذه السنوات،
I thought
ظننت
she was dead.
لقد ماتت.
The whole time...
طوال الوقت...
If you're
إذا كنت
as innocent as you claim,
براءتك كما تدّعي،
you could tell all this to the police.
يمكنك إخبار الشرطة بكل هذا.
I'm innocent,
أنا بريء،
but I don't deal with the police.
لكنني لا أتعامل مع الشرطة.
I'm not used to talking to them.
أنا لست معتاداً على التحدث معهم.
Besides,
بجانب،
Xu Peng has been dead for years.
لقد توفي شو بنغ منذ سنوات.
Does the truth
هل الحقيقة
matter anymore?
هل ما زال الأمر مهماً؟
It does.
نعم، هذا صحيح.
At least, it matters to your daughter.
على الأقل، هذا الأمر يهم ابنتك.
You should tell Wu Feifei
يجب أن تخبر وو فيفي
that all these years,
طوال هذه السنوات،
she wasn't someone without a mother.
لم تكن شخصاً بلا أم.
No.
لا.
Give me some time.
أعطني بعض الوقت.
I'll send Feifei away.
سأرسل فيفي بعيدًا.
Whatever you want,
أياً كان ما تريد،
just say it.
قلها فحسب.
Come at me.
هيا واجهني.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
we're negotiating now.
نحن نتفاوض الآن.
If it goes well,
إذا سارت الأمور على ما يرام،
you hand the thing over to me.
سلمني الشيء.
If it doesn't,
وإذا لم يحدث ذلك،
you still hand it over.
ما زلت تسلمه.
I haven't done this in a long time.
لم أفعل هذا منذ فترة طويلة.
Doing it again so suddenly,
القيام بذلك مجدداً بهذه السرعة المفاجئة،
I'm a bit rusty.
أنا لستُ متمرساً تماماً.
I thought
ظننت
I'd never have to do this again.
لن أضطر إلى فعل هذا مرة أخرى.
Stop wasting everyone's time.
توقف عن إضاعة وقت الجميع.
You're impulsive.
أنت شخص مندفع.
You're young.
أنت صغير السن.
You don't think things through.
أنت لا تفكر في الأمور جيداً.
I'll give you one more chance.
سأمنحك فرصة أخرى.
By 10:00 PM tomorrow,
بحلول الساعة العاشرة مساءً غداً،
bring it to Chen Kang yourself.
أحضرها بنفسك إلى تشين كانغ.
How do you plan to explain this to your daughter?
كيف تخططين لشرح هذا لابنتك؟
Explain what?
اشرح ماذا؟
You lied to her for so many years.
لقد كذبت عليها لسنوات عديدة.
Do you plan to keep lying for the rest of her life?
هل تنوي الاستمرار في الكذب عليها طوال حياتها؟
This is our family matter.
هذا شأن عائلي.
Your family matter?
هل عائلتك مهمة؟
Fine.
بخير.
I gave you a chance.
لقد منحتك فرصة.
Help!
يساعد!
Who is it?
من هذا؟
- Don't touch me! - Dong.
- لا تلمسني! - دونغ.
- It's me.
- أنا هو.
You're safe now.
أنت بأمان الآن.
Feng!
فينغ!
Why did you take so long?
لماذا استغرقت كل هذا الوقت؟
Feng.
فينغ.
I thought I'd never see you again.
ظننت أنني لن أراك مرة أخرى.
Feng...
فينغ...
Feng, it was terrifying.
فينغ، كان الأمر مرعباً.
(I'm Gao Feng.)
(أنا جاو فنغ.)
(An orphan.)
(يتيم.)
(To me,)
(لي،)
(being an orphan isn't just identity,)
(كونك يتيماً لا يقتصر على الهوية فقط)
(it's a mystery.)
(إنه لغز.)
(But lately,)
(لكن في الآونة الأخيرة،)
(it feels like I'm waking up from it.)
(أشعر وكأنني أستيقظ من ذلك.)
(The road ahead is full of thorns,)
(الطريق أمامنا مليء بالأشواك،)
(but my mind has never been clearer.)
(لكن ذهني لم يكن يومًا أكثر صفاءً.)
(I see with my bleeding eyes)
(أرى بعيني الدامية)
(and run on my bleeding legs.)
(وأركض على ساقي التي تنزف.)
(Even if I'm broken into pieces,)
(حتى لو تحطمت إلى أشلاء،)
(I know)
(أنا أعرف)
(as long as I run toward the end,)
(طالما أنني أركض حتى النهاية،)
(I'll see the beginning of my life.)
(سأرى بداية حياتي.)
(Nothing will stop me.)
(لن يوقفني شيء.)
=Episode 11= =Golden Ball=
=الحلقة 11= =الكرة الذهبية=
(Grave of Beloved Wife, Li Hongyue)
(قبر الزوجة الحبيبة، لي هونغيو)
It's chilly.
الجو بارد.
Don't catch a cold, Feifei.
لا تصابي بنزلة برد يا فيفي.
How many lies are you still telling?
كم عدد الأكاذيب التي ما زلت ترويها؟
Answer me!
يجيبني!
You think I'm not hurting?
أتظن أنني لا أتألم؟
You think I don't feel pain?
أتظن أنني لا أشعر بالألم؟
- Stop it! - I...
- توقف عن ذلك! - أنا...
Feifei,
فيفي,
come home.
عد إلى المنزل.
Let's go home.
هيا بنا إلى المنزل.
(Early 1990s)
(أوائل التسعينيات)
Qu Meng.
تشو منغ.
Hurry up.
أسرع.
What Qu Meng?
ماذا عن كو مينغ؟
All you ever know
كل ما تعرفه
is Qu Meng.
هو كو مينغ.
What do you want?
ماذا تريد؟
You're here.
أنت هنا.
How are you feeling?
كيف تشعر؟
Any reactions lately?
هل من ردود فعل حديثة؟
I'm fine. Nothing wrong.
أنا بخير. لا يوجد أي شيء خاطئ.
Where's Qu Meng?
أين كو مينغ؟
I'll help you find her.
سأساعدك في العثور عليها.
Hey. Wait.
مهلاً. انتظر.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Did he suspect anything?
هل كان يشك في أي شيء؟
No.
لا.
Wrap the bandage tighter.
لف الضمادة بإحكام أكبر.
In another month or two,
في غضون شهر أو شهرين آخرين،
you won't be able to hide it.
لن تتمكن من إخفائه.
I'll hide it for as long as I can.
سأخفيه لأطول فترة ممكنة.
It probably likes hearing me sing.
ربما يستمتع بسماع غنائي.
Every time I sing, it kicks.
في كل مرة أغني فيها، أشعر بحماس شديد.
I really couldn't hold it in just now.
لم أستطع كتمان الأمر الآن.
They say a mother and her child are connected.
يقولون إن الأم وطفلها مرتبطان.
I believe the baby
أعتقد أن الطفل
can feel how I feel.
يستطيع أن يشعر بما أشعر به.
Come.
يأتي.
Hold your breath.
احبس أنفاسك.
Forget it.
انسى ذلك.
Don't sing tonight.
لا تغني الليلة.
Thank you, Ms. Hong.
شكراً لكِ يا آنسة هونغ.
It feels so nice!
إنه شعور رائع!
Tell me honestly.
قل لي بصراحة.
Have you ever hated me?
هل كرهتني يوماً؟
Yes.
نعم.
Of course I have.
بالطبع فعلت.
If you hadn't been waiting for me at the gate
لو لم تكن تنتظرني عند البوابة
the day I got out,
في اليوم الذي خرجت فيه،
my life might've turned out very differently.
ربما كانت حياتي ستسير بشكل مختلف تماماً.
But hating you doesn't help.
لكن كرهك لا يفيد.
Now that you understand me and protect me,
الآن وقد فهمتني وتحميني،
I'm grateful.
أنا ممتن.
There's no such thing as "what if".
لا يوجد شيء اسمه "ماذا لو".
Only karma
الكارما فقط
and the outcome we're heading toward.
والنتيجة التي نتجه نحوها.
Don't get it, do you?
ألا تفهم ذلك؟
Yang Wenyuan told me that.
أخبرني يانغ وينيوان بذلك.
Sounds deep, right?
يبدو الأمر عميقاً، أليس كذلك؟
♪I give long roads to the distant horizon♪
♪أمنح طرقًا طويلة للأفق البعيد♪
♪I give roses to love♪
أهدي الورود للحب
♪What can I give you♪
♪ماذا يمكنني أن أقدم لك؟♪
♪My lover?♪
♪حبيبي؟♪
♪I give white clouds to the meadow♪
أهدي الغيوم البيضاء للمرج
♪I give rivers to the ocean♪
♪أهدي الأنهار إلى المحيط♪
♪What can I give you♪
♪ماذا يمكنني أن أقدم لك؟♪
♪My friend?♪
♪صديقي؟♪
The most dangerous place
أخطر مكان
is the safest place, right?
أليس هذا المكان الأكثر أماناً؟
There's no such thing as absolute safety.
لا يوجد شيء اسمه أمان مطلق.
This place makes the most sense
هذا المكان هو الأنسب
out of all the options I could think of.
من بين جميع الخيارات التي خطرت ببالي.
After Yang Wenyuan passed,
بعد وفاة يانغ وينيوان،
did you come back?
هل عدت؟
I didn't dare to.
لم أجرؤ على ذلك.
(Look, our club is new)
(انظروا، نادينا جديد)
to the real estate business.
في مجال العقارات.
We need someone
نحن بحاجة إلى شخص ما
to oversee things in Shenzhen.
للإشراف على الأمور في شنتشن.
Emotionally speaking,
من الناحية العاطفية،
Hongyue is pregnant now.
هونغيو حامل الآن.
As a husband and father-to-be,
بصفتي زوجاً وأباً منتظراً،
it doesn't feel right not to stay with her.
لا أشعر بالراحة لعدم البقاء معها.
But practically speaking,
لكن من الناحية العملية،
a lot of people are relying on this project
يعتمد الكثير من الناس على هذا المشروع
to make a living.
لكسب الرزق.
I wouldn't feel right not going either.
لن أشعر بالراحة إن لم أذهب أيضاً.
How about this, Wu?
ما رأيك بهذا يا وو؟
I'll make the call for you.
سأقوم بالاتصال نيابةً عنك.
You go to Shenzhen first.
تذهب إلى شنتشن أولاً.
During this time,
خلال هذه الفترة،
it doesn't matter if you can't stay with me.
لا يهم إن لم تستطع البقاء معي.
But for the group,
أما بالنسبة للمجموعة،
it's critical.
إنه أمر بالغ الأهمية.
Right, Mr. Xu?
أليس كذلك يا سيد شو؟
So Wu,
سو وو،
you head over first.
توجه إلى هناك أولاً.
When I'm close to my due date, you come back.
عندما يقترب موعد ولادتي، ستعود.
Just six months.
ستة أشهر فقط.
I'll be back by the end of the year.
سأعود بحلول نهاية العام.
Once the baby's born, I'll come back right away, okay?
بمجرد ولادة الطفل، سأعود على الفور، حسناً؟
Good, Mr. Wu.
جيد يا سيد وو.
I must raise a toast to you.
لا بد لي من أن أرفع نخبًا لك.
- Sure. - Cheers.
- بالتأكيد. - بالهناء والشفاء.
Then it's settled.
إذن، تم حسم الأمر.
A toast to Hongyue.
نخب لهونج يو.
Alright, Mr. Xu.
حسناً، سيد شو.
That settles
هذا ينهي الأمر
Wu's part.
دور وو.
But I do have
لكن لدي
something personal.
شيء شخصي.
Go ahead.
تفضل.
The doctor says
يقول الطبيب
the baby's a bit big.
الطفل كبير الحجم قليلاً.
It won't be very convenient
لن يكون الأمر مريحاً للغاية
to stay at the club.
للبقاء في النادي.
I'm thinking of moving out.
أفكر في الانتقال من هنا.
Yes.
نعم.
The club's too chaotic.
النادي فوضوي للغاية.
It's better to move out.
من الأفضل الانتقال.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Whatever Mr. Wu decides.
أياً كان ما يقرره السيد وو.
Thank you, Mr. Xu.
شكراً لك يا سيد شو.
Also, I'll take Qu Meng with me.
سأصطحب كو مينغ معي أيضاً.
Why take Qu Meng?
لماذا تأخذ تشو منغ؟
If you're gone, Qu Meng can fill in for you.
إذا كنت غائباً، يمكن لـ Qu Meng أن يحل محلك.
If she leaves too, who's going to run things here?
وإذا رحلت هي الأخرى، فمن سيدير ​​الأمور هنا؟
Mr. Xu,
السيد شو،
the club can't run on
لا يمكن للنادي أن يستمر على
just Qu Meng and me forever.
أنا وكو مينغ فقط إلى الأبد.
Right?
يمين؟
He Xiaohong can do a good job, too.
هي شياوهونغ تستطيع القيام بعمل جيد أيضاً.
You've seen that.
لقد رأيت ذلك.
She needs more chances to train, right?
إنها بحاجة إلى المزيد من الفرص للتدريب، أليس كذلك؟
No matter how busy work gets,
مهما بلغ انشغالنا بالعمل،
I have to look after Ms. Hong.
عليّ أن أعتني بالسيدة هونغ.
Mr. Wu.
السيد وو.
I'll thank you in advance.
أشكرك مقدماً.
I'll finish all.
سأنهي كل شيء.
Xu, Qu Meng
شو، تشو منغ
is good at everything,
هو بارع في كل شيء،
but she has
لكنها تمتلك
a short fuse.
سريع الغضب.
Only Hongyue
هونغيو فقط
can keep her in line.
بإمكانه أن يُبقيها تحت السيطرة.
She can also take care of Hongyue.
كما يمكنها أن تعتني بهونغيو.
I think it works.
أعتقد أنها ناجحة.
Let's settle it that way.
فلنحسم الأمر بهذه الطريقة.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Since it's your family matter, you decide.
بما أنها مسألة عائلية، فالقرار لك.
I'm looking into Gao Dahua.
أبحث في موضوع غاو داهوا.
That cook.
ذلك الطباخ.
(He seems honest.)
(يبدو صادقاً.)
(You can never really tell.)
(لا يمكنك الجزم بذلك أبداً.)
(Don't be so naive.)
(لا تكن ساذجاً إلى هذا الحد.)
(Anyone working in a club)
(أي شخص يعمل في نادٍ)
(isn't truly honest.)
(ليس صادقاً حقاً.)
I checked into it.
لقد تحققت من الأمر.
His family
عائلته
has been wanting a child.
كانت ترغب في إنجاب طفل.
Do you think I'm cruel?
هل تعتقد أنني قاسٍ؟
No mother
لا أم
is truly cruel.
إنه أمر قاسٍ حقاً.
Do you believe in reincarnation?
هل تؤمن بالتناسخ؟
I didn't before.
لم أفعل ذلك من قبل.
But now...
لكن الآن...
I do.
أفعل.
This life is already set.
هذه الحياة مُقدّرة سلفاً.
All I can do is to live well
كل ما أستطيع فعله هو أن أعيش حياة جيدة
and earn blessings for the next one.
ونسأل الله أن يبارك لنا في المرة القادمة.
You haven't had the noodles I made
لم تتذوق المعكرونة التي صنعتها
in a long time, have you?
هل فعلت ذلك منذ فترة طويلة؟
Stop acting in front of me.
توقف عن التمثيل أمامي.
You insisted on sending me to Shenzhen,
أصررتَ على إرسالي إلى شينزن،
acting all reasonable and big-hearted.
يتصرفون بعقلانية وكرم.
Who were you putting on a show for?
لمن كنت تقدم هذا العرض؟
But if I can keep acting long enough,
لكن إذا استطعت الاستمرار في التمثيل لفترة كافية،
doesn't it become real?
ألا يصبح الأمر حقيقياً؟
You fight out there in front,
أنت تقاتل هناك في المقدمة،
and I stay behind
وأبقى في الخلف
and support you.
وسندعمك.
Ming will go to Shenzhen with me.
سيذهب مينغ معي إلى شينزن.
I'll find another driver.
سأجد سائقاً آخر.
I think Zhang Biao is fine.
أعتقد أن تشانغ بياو بخير.
Let him drive for you
دعه يقود السيارة نيابة عنك
and run errands.
والقيام بالمهام.
He likes money,
إنه يحب المال،
but other than that, he's not a bad person.
لكن بخلاف ذلك، فهو ليس شخصًا سيئًا.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
In your heart,
في قلبك،
what are you to me?
ماذا تمثل لي؟
Be honest.
كن صادقاً.
A woman.
امرأة.
I'm your woman.
أنا المرأة التي تريدها.
I see you as my woman, too.
أراكِ أيضاً امرأتي.
The woman I love.
المرأة التي أحبها.
You're pregnant now,
أنتِ حامل الآن،
and I can't stay by your side.
ولا أستطيع البقاء بجانبك.
I feel terrible, honestly.
أشعر بالسوء الشديد، بصراحة.
Maybe when I come back from Shenzhen,
ربما عندما أعود من شينزن،
I'll already be a father,
سأكون أباً بالفعل،
and you'll be a mother.
وستصبحين أماً.
I wonder if things between us
أتساءل عما إذا كانت الأمور بيننا
will change after the baby is born.
سيتغير ذلك بعد ولادة الطفل.
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
I don't know, either.
لا أعرف أيضاً.
We'll see.
سنرى.
♪I come to the street entrance♪
♪أصل إلى مدخل الشارع♪
(There are two things)
(هناك شيئان)
(that never change,)
(التي لا تتغير أبداً،)
(no matter how much time passes.)
(بغض النظر عن مقدار الوقت الذي يمر.)
(One is something you're born with.)
(أحدها شيء يولد المرء به.)
(Blood ties.)
(روابط الدم.)
(Who your parents are)
(من هما والداك)
(can't be changed.)
(لا يمكن تغييره.)
(The other)
(الآخر)
(is karma.)
(هذا هو الكارما.)
(One must bear the consequences)
(يجب على المرء أن يتحمل العواقب)
(for what they have done,)
(بسبب ما فعلوه)
(whether good or bad.)
(سواء كان ذلك جيداً أم سيئاً.)
Qu Meng...
تشو منغ...
(There'll always be a day of reckoning.)
(سيأتي يوم الحساب لا محالة.)
Hongyue...
هونجيو...
(That's justice and conscience.)
(هذا هو العدل والضمير.)
♪Reluctant to leave my neighbors♪
♪أتردد في مغادرة جيراني♪
♪And my good friends♪
♪وأصدقائي الأعزاء♪
♪I cannot bear to watch my mother grow old♪
لا أطيق أن أرى أمي تكبر في السن
♪A child is a mother's flesh and blood♪
♪الطفل هو لحم ودم الأم♪
Are you feeling better?
هل تشعر بتحسن؟
If you run into any trouble, come to us.
إذا واجهتك أي مشكلة، فتعال إلينا.
Don't hurt yourself like this again.
لا تؤذي نفسك هكذا مرة أخرى.
I don't know...
لا أعرف...
Madam, please take a look at this.
سيدتي، أرجو منكِ إلقاء نظرة على هذا.
Do you know her?
هل تعرفها؟
She's been using your identity
لقد كانت تستخدم هويتك
to move around Binchuan recently.
للتنقل في بينتشوان مؤخراً.
I don't know!
لا أعرف!
I don't know her!
لا أعرفها!
We won't hurt you.
لن نؤذيك.
I don't know her! I really don't!
لا أعرفها! حقاً لا أعرفها!
Madam, we won't hurt you.
سيدتي، لن نؤذيك.
Please don't hurt yourself.
من فضلك لا تؤذي نفسك.
Alright. I won't touch you.
حسناً. لن ألمسك.
Don't worry. I won't hurt you.
لا تقلق. لن أؤذيك.
Take a deep breath.
خذ نفسًا عميقًا.
Madam, I don't know what you went through,
سيدتي، لا أعرف ما مررتِ به.
but please trust us.
لكن ثق بنا من فضلك.
We're here to protect you.
نحن هنا لحمايتك.
But you have to tell us
لكن عليك أن تخبرنا
what you know.
ما تعرفه.
Only then can we protect you.
عندها فقط نستطيع حمايتك.
Can you tell me
هل يمكن أن تخبرني
what kind of place
أي نوع من الأماكن
the International Club is?
ما هو النادي الدولي؟
Young girl, do you want to go to the International Club?
يا فتاة صغيرة، هل ترغبين في الذهاب إلى النادي الدولي؟
That place is full of big shots and celebrities.
ذلك المكان مليء بالشخصيات المهمة والمشاهير.
You have to sing and dance well.
عليك أن تجيد الغناء والرقص.
The lights stay on all night.
تبقى الأضواء مضاءة طوال الليل.
(The music never stops.)
(الموسيقى لا تتوقف أبداً.)
(There's drinking.)
(يوجد شرب.)
If you're tired, you sleep.
إذا كنت متعباً، فأنت تنام.
Don't go.
لا تذهب.
Never go there...
لا تذهب إلى هناك أبداً...
Tonight,
الليلة،
he'll have to explain everything about the International Club,
سيتعين عليه أن يشرح كل شيء عن النادي الدولي.
your mother,
والدتك،
and my mother.
وأمي.
Lay everything out once and for all.
ضع كل شيء في مكانه مرة واحدة وإلى الأبد.
Where your family goes from here
إلى أين ستتجه عائلتك من هنا
depends on your choice.
يعتمد الأمر على اختيارك.
10:00 PM tonight. I'll wait for your answer.
الساعة العاشرة مساءً الليلة. سأنتظر ردك.
I'll make dinner. It'll be ready soon.
سأُحضّر العشاء. سيكون جاهزاً قريباً.
I was impulsive last night.
كنتُ مندفعًا الليلة الماضية.
Let's talk somewhere else.
لنتحدث في مكان آخر.
Young people shouldn't think too small.
لا ينبغي للشباب أن يفكروا بشكل محدود للغاية.
You can't give up on your future
لا يمكنك التخلي عن مستقبلك
because of your parents' generation.
بسبب جيل والديك.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
our group
مجموعتنا
has businesses and projects all over the world.
لديها أعمال ومشاريع في جميع أنحاء العالم.
You like hiking, don't you?
أنت تحب رياضة المشي لمسافات طويلة، أليس كذلك؟
The Alps.
جبال الألب.
Mount Kilimanjaro.
جبل كليمنجارو.
We have travel agencies for that.
لدينا وكالات سفر لهذا الغرض.
If you like the sea,
إذا كنت تحب البحر،
we also have projects
لدينا أيضاً مشاريع
in the Caribbean and Hawaii.
في منطقة البحر الكاريبي وهاواي.
Our company needs
شركتنا بحاجة
young people like you.
شباب مثلك.
Pick a place
اختر مكانًا
and start over.
وابدأ من جديد.
Mr. Wu, you're capable of anything.
السيد وو، أنت قادر على فعل أي شيء.
I don't think I'll ever get a clean start
لا أعتقد أنني سأحصل على بداية جديدة أبداً
wherever I go.
أينما أذهب.
One bad morning for you,
صباح سيء بالنسبة لك،
one phone call,
مكالمة هاتفية واحدة،
and I'd be wiped out,
وسأُباد تماماً.
just like my mother.
تماماً مثل أمي.
What kind of talk is that?
ما هذا الكلام؟
I'm a businessman.
أنا رجل أعمال.
I'm nobody.
أنا لا أحد.
Standing here
أقف هنا
talking to someone like you is not easy for me.
التحدث إلى شخص مثلك ليس بالأمر السهل بالنسبة لي.
Mr. Wu, you're astute.
السيد وو، أنت ذكي.
You've got a good grasp of things.
لديك فهم جيد للأمور.
Matters of your generation,
شؤون جيلكم،
money, and power...
المال والسلطة...
You can deal with all that.
يمكنك التعامل مع كل ذلك.
But when it comes to our generation,
لكن عندما يتعلق الأمر بجيلنا،
to blood ties,
إلى روابط الدم،
and to feelings,
وإلى المشاعر،
you can't.
لا يمكنك.
Mr. Wu, think about this instead.
سيد وو، فكر في هذا بدلاً من ذلك.
What would your daughter do for her mother?
ماذا ستفعل ابنتك من أجل والدتها؟
Go talk to her.
اذهب وتحدث معها.
I've told her everything I needed to say.
لقد أخبرتها بكل ما كنت بحاجة إلى قوله.
Stop.
قف.
I warned you.
لقد حذرتك.
Don't mess with my daughter.
لا تعبث مع ابنتي.
(After learning about the International Club,)
(بعد التعرف على النادي الدولي،)
(I often come here.)
(أتردد على هذا المكان كثيراً.)
(I come here)
(أنا آتي إلى هنا)
(to see where I came from.)
(لأرى من أين أتيت.)
(I told you.)
(أخبرتك.)
I have ways and means
لديّ طرق ووسائل
to deal with you.
للتعامل معك.
Excuse me.
اعذرني.
We're Long Yu's parents.
نحن والدا لونغ يو.
Who signed the consent form
من قام بتوقيع نموذج الموافقة؟
for Long Yu's surgery?
هل هذا من أجل جراحة لونغ يو؟
I did.
فعلتُ.
I'm Gao Feng's mother.
أنا والدة غاو فنغ.
Please don't worry.
لا تقلق من فضلك.
She'll have all the treatments she needs.
ستتلقى جميع العلاجات التي تحتاجها.
We cover the medical expenses.
نحن نغطي النفقات الطبية.
Why should you get to decide for my daughter?
لماذا يحق لك أن تقرر نيابة عن ابنتي؟
We have money.
لدينا مال.
Long Yu shouldn't be staying here at all.
لا ينبغي أن يبقى لونغ يو هنا على الإطلاق.
Alright. Enough.
حسناً. كفى.
Gao Feng,
جاو فنغ
you're the one
أنت الشخص المناسب
who put Long Yu through all this.
من الذي تسبب في كل هذا لـ لونغ يو؟
I don't care about your personal mess.
لا أهتم بمشاكلك الشخصية.
But you can't drag my daughter into it.
لكن لا يمكنك إقحام ابنتي في هذا الأمر.
Let's be clear.
لنكن واضحين.
We're not here
لسنا هنا
to ask for compensation.
للمطالبة بالتعويض.
But if anything happens to Long Yu,
لكن إذا حدث أي مكروه للونغ يو،
I won't let this slide.
لن أدع هذا يمر مرور الكرام.
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدًا،
you're not allowed to get near her.
ممنوع عليك الاقتراب منها.
Once we're back,
بمجرد عودتنا،
we'll transfer her to another hospital.
سننقلها إلى مستشفى آخر.
I'm sorry, Mr. Long and Mrs. Long.
أنا آسف، سيد لونغ والسيدة لونغ.
What happened to Long Yu is on me.
ما حدث لونغ يو هو مسؤوليتي.
I'll take responsibility.
سأتحمل المسؤولية.
You don't even know who you are,
أنت لا تعرف حتى من أنت،
do you?
هل أنت؟
Take responsibility?
هل تتحمل المسؤولية؟
Why don't you get your own life in order first?
لماذا لا تُرتّب حياتك أولاً؟
You spawn.
أنت تظهر.
Young man,
شاب،
take my advice.
خذ بنصيحتي.
Be realistic.
كن واقعياً.
Mind your own business.
اهتم بشؤونك الخاصة.
Mr. Wu told you that, right?
أخبرك السيد وو بذلك، أليس كذلك؟
This tea
هذا الشاي
tastes exactly like the one
طعمه مطابق تماماً للطعم الأصلي
I had in Mr. Wu's office.
كان ذلك في مكتب السيد وو.
Knowing Long Yu,
معرفة لونغ يو،
she wouldn't have told you about me
ما كانت لتخبرك عني
in such detail.
بهذه التفاصيل.
Also, your daughter just came out of surgery.
كما أن ابنتك قد خرجت لتوها من عملية جراحية.
She hasn't even woken up yet.
لم تستيقظ بعد.
You're telling me to mind my own business
أنت تقول لي أن أهتم بشؤوني الخاصة
and rushing to take her away.
وسارعوا لأخذها بعيداً.
Is that how parents talk?
هل هذه هي طريقة حديث الآباء؟
You!
أنت!
You can call me a spawn.
يمكنك أن تسميني نسلاً.
I don't care.
لا أهتم.
I don't envy families
لا أحسد العائلات
like yours anyway.
على أي حال، مثلك.
- What? - Mr. Long and Mrs. Long,
- ماذا؟ - السيد لونغ والسيدة لونغ،
let me make my position clear.
دعوني أوضح موقفي.
Long Yu is my family.
لونغ يو هي عائلتي.
I won't let you take her away.
لن أسمح لك بأخذها بعيداً.
- What are you doing? - Talk properly.
- ماذا تفعل؟ - تحدث بشكل لائق.
Why hit him?
لماذا ضربته؟
Old geezer,
رجل عجوز،
I'll take that slap
سأتقبل تلك الصفعة
for Long Yu.
لونغ يو.
But you don't deserve to hit me again.
لكنك لا تستحق أن تضربني مرة أخرى.
Look at this.
انظر إلى هذا.
This is a Guardianship Agreement.
هذا اتفاق وصاية.
It's legally notarized.
تم توثيقها قانونياً.
Long Yu and I
أنا ولونغ يو
are each other's legal guardians.
كل منهما ولي أمر قانوني للآخر.
I travel a lot,
أسافر كثيراً،
so I asked her to help me sign.
لذا طلبت منها أن تساعدني في التوقيع.
I didn't know
لم أكن أعرف
she'd also transfer her guardianship rights
كما أنها ستنقل حقوق الوصاية الخاصة بها
to me.
لي.
So compared to me,
بالمقارنة بي،
you're the unrelated ones, understand?
أنتم الأشخاص غير المرتبطين ببعضهم البعض، هل تفهمون؟
We're her biological parents.
نحن والداها البيولوجيان.
She left home as a teenager.
غادرت منزلها في سن المراهقة.
All you ever did was send money. You never took care of her.
كل ما فعلته هو إرسال المال. لم تعتني بها قط.
Parents, huh?
الآباء، هاه؟
Since Mr. Wu sent you,
بما أن السيد وو هو من أرسلك،
tell him this.
أخبره بهذا.
No one
لا احد
is taking Long Yu away but me.
هو يأخذ لونغ يو بعيدًا، لكنني أنا.
Let's eat, Dad.
هيا نأكل يا أبي.
(C2-0930)
(C2-0930)
♪For an answer♪
♪للحصول على إجابة♪
♪You stand guard alone outside the door♪
♪تقف حارساً وحيداً خارج الباب♪
♪The obsession held within is sharp♪
♪الهوس الكامن في الداخل حاد♪
♪It cuts through everything, leaving no way back♪
♪يقطع كل شيء، ولا يترك أي سبيل للعودة♪
♪Cobwebs are woven into a net♪
♪تُنسج خيوط العنكبوت في شبكة♪
♪Each strand is a lead♪
♪كل خصلة هي خيط رئيسي♪
♪Fate hangs above your head like a suspended blade♪
♪القدر معلق فوق رأسك كشفرة معلقة♪
♪You swallow so much frustration♪
♪تكتم الكثير من الإحباط♪
♪And push the door open with your own hands♪
♪ وادفع الباب بيديك ♪
♪What's meant to come will always come♪
♪ما قُدِّر له أن يأتي سيأتي حتماً♪
♪You stop the pendulum of hesitation♪
♪توقف عن التردد♪
♪Only when darkness admits it is dark♪
♪فقط عندما يعترف الظلام بأنه مظلم♪
♪Can innocence return to the light♪
هل يمكن للبراءة أن تعود إلى النور؟
♪The curtain of the truth is drawn aside♪
♪ سُحب ستار الحقيقة جانباً♪
♪You cross through pain to reach the other shore♪
♪تتجاوز الألم لتصل إلى الشاطئ الآخر♪
♪You demand tears to come crashing down♪
♪تطالبين بدموعٍ تنهمر بغزارة♪
♪You demand old dreams to grow into rainbows♪
♪تطالبين بتحويل الأحلام القديمة إلى ألوان قوس قزح♪
♪You demand dust to stir up raging waves♪
♪أنت تطلب الغبار لإثارة أمواج عاتية♪
♪Souls will rise again♪
♪ستنهض الأرواح من جديد♪
♪You demand that fate turn generous from now on♪
♪تطالب بأن يصبح القدر كريماً من الآن فصاعداً♪
♪To return everything it once took from you♪
♪لإعادة كل ما أخذه منك ذات مرة♪
♪You demand tomorrow♪
♪أنت تطالب بالغد♪
♪To bloom beyond the ruins♪
♪لتزهر من وراء الأنقاض♪
♪The light will come♪
سيأتي النور
♪Who keeps warmth alive♪
♪من يحافظ على الدفء حياً♪
♪And beholds flowers bloom in the abyss?♪
♪هل ترى الزهور تتفتح في الهاوية؟♪
♪Who never stops calling out♪
♪من لا يتوقف عن النداء♪
♪And finally opens their eyes♪
♪وأخيراً يفتحون أعينهم♪
♪From a long slumber?♪
♪هل أنت قادم من سبات طويل؟♪
♪The light will come♪
سيأتي النور
♪You demand to pass through life's perils in peace♪
♪تطالب بالمرور عبر مخاطر الحياة بسلام♪
♪You demand to decide your own fate♪
♪أنت تطالب بتحديد مصيرك بنفسك♪
♪You demand the future♪
♪أنتم تطالبون بالمستقبل♪
♪To flourish right before your eyes♪
♪لتزدهر أمام عينيك مباشرة♪
♪The light will come♪
سيأتي النور